<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<c:component type="chSourceHighlighting" componentId="chSourceHighlighting_1" xmlns:c="http://com.snnmo.website">
  <c:abstract>
    <![CDATA[
    <div style="font-family:monospace;">
     After we published the iCloud programming tutorial, the first question from our readers is not about iCloud but related to the static table view. 
     If you’ve followed our tutorials, you should have a basic understanding about table view. 
     However, the table views that we’ve covered are of dynamic content. 
     The “Add Note” controller that we built in the previous tutorial, on the other hand, makes use of the static table view. 
     If you have problem with static table view, this tutorial is for you. 
     We’ll show you how to create static table view using Storyboard.
     <br />
     <br />
     To illustrate how easy you can use Storyboard to implement static table view, we’ll build a simple Setting screen.
     Static table views are ideal in situations where a pre-defined number of data items to be displayed. 
     A setting screen is an obvious use of static table view.
</div>
    ]]>
  </c:abstract>

  <c:hero type="image">http://www.appcoda.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Static-Table-View-Demo-App1.jpg</c:hero>

  <c:entry style="margin-top:1em;color:rgb(156, 25, 197);font-weight:bold;">
    <c:title>Creating Xcode Project</c:title>
    <c:desc>
      <c:desc1>
        <![CDATA[
          
        ]]>
      </c:desc1>
    </c:desc>

    <c:sourceContent type="html" title="" id="sourceContent1" style="background-color:white;"
                     bodyStyle="padding:0;font-size:1.2em;">
      <![CDATA[
        <div>To get started, launch Xcode and create a new project using the Single View Application template.</div>
        <div style="margin:1em 0;">
          <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://www.appcoda.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/New-Xcode-Project-Static-Table.jpg" />
        </div>
        
        <div>Name your project as “StaticTableDemo” and don’t forget to select “Storyboard” in your project setting.</div>
        <div style="margin:1em 0;">
          <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://www.appcoda.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Static-Table-Project-Setting.jpg" />
        </div>
      ]]>
    </c:sourceContent>
    <c:comment style="margin-top:2em;">
      <c:comment1 style="color:black;">
        <![CDATA[
                ]]>
      </c:comment1>
    </c:comment>
  </c:entry>

  <c:entry style="margin-top:1em;color:rgb(156, 25, 197);font-weight:bold;">
    <c:title>Designing Static Table View</c:title>
    <c:desc>
      <c:desc1>
        <![CDATA[
          
        ]]>
      </c:desc1>
    </c:desc>

    <c:sourceContent type="html" title="" id="sourceContent1" style="background-color:white;"
                     bodyStyle="padding:0;font-size:1.2em;">
      <![CDATA[
        <div>In Storyboard, first delete the default view controller and drag a Table View Controller from the Object library.</div>
        <div style="margin:1em 0;">
          <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://www.appcoda.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Static-Table-Table-View-Controller.jpg" />
        </div>
        
        <div>By default, Xcode sets the table view for dynamic content. You can easily change the table view from dynamic to static cells by altering the content property. Once changed, you’ll have a table view with three empty static cells.</div>
        <div style="margin:1em 0;">
          <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://www.appcoda.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Change-to-Static-Cells.jpg" />
        </div>
        
        <div>To get the desired view of the Settings screen, change the table style from “Plain” to “Grouped” in the Attributes inspector of the table view. You have two ways to change the number of table row from 3 to 2. The easiest way is to select one of the table rows and press delete button to remove it. Alternatively, select the Table View Section in the document navigator and change the row number.</div>
        <div style="margin:1em 0;">
          <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://www.appcoda.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Static-Table-View-Section.jpg" />
        </div>
      ]]>
    </c:sourceContent>
    <c:comment style="margin-top:2em;">
      <c:comment1 style="color:black;">
        <![CDATA[
                ]]>
      </c:comment1>
    </c:comment>
  </c:entry>

</c:component>
