<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<c:component type="chHtmlContent" componentId="chHtmlContent_1" xmlns:c="http://com.snnmo.website">
	<c:content>
    <![CDATA[ 
       <p>
        If you are bored with default Ambiance theme and icons in Ubuntu 13.10, why not try changing icons or the theme completely? 
        In this article I am going to show you how to install themes in Ubuntu 14.04 and 13.10.
        
        <br />
        This article was originally written for Ubuntu 13.10 but it is equally applicable to Ubuntu 14.04.
       </p>
       
       <h4 style="font-weight:bold;font-size:1.5em;margin-top:1.5em;margin-bottom:1.0em;">Install a theme in Ubuntu 13.10:</h4>
       <p>
         First thing of course is to get a good theme. 
         You can try any of these <a target="_blank" href="http://itsfoss.com/best-themes-ubuntu-1310/">5 best themes for Ubuntu 13.10</a> or <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ubuntuthemes.org/">www.ubuntuthemes.org</a>, 
         but in this tutorial I’ll use <a target="_blank" href="http://satya164.deviantart.com/art/Numix-GTK3-theme-360223962">Numix</a>. 
         It has an appearance of iOS, to an extent. I am going to show you the installation of a theme with Numix theme and 
         <a target="_blank" href="http://itsfoss.com/unity-tweak-tool-the-best-tweak-tool-for-ubuntu-may-be-not/">Unity Tweak Tool</a>. 
         If you are using Gnome instead of Unity desktop environment, you can use Gnome Tweak Tool.
       </p>
       
       <h4 style="font-weight:bold;font-size:1.5em;margin-top:1.5em;margin-bottom:1.0em;">Install Unity Tweak Tool:</h4>
       <p>
         Open a terminal and use the following command: <br /><br />

         <b>sudo apt-get install unity-tweak-tool</b><br /><br />
         Please note that Unity Tweak Tool is available in software sources of Ubuntu 13.10 but you might have to install it via a PPA in older versions.
       </p>
       
       <h4 style="font-weight:bold;font-size:1.5em;margin-top:1.5em;margin-bottom:1.0em;">Install the theme:</h4>
       <p>
         Now this is tricky here. Numix can be easily installed through a PPA. But if you have downloaded the theme in zipped folder, extract the content in ~/.themes directory. If you don’t have such directory, create one.
         <br /><br />
         To install Numix theme in Ubuntu 13.10 via PPA, use the following command:
         <br /><br />
         <b>
         sudo add-apt-repository ppa:numix/ppa <br />
         sudo apt-get update <br />
         sudo apt-get install numix-gtk-theme numix-icon-theme numix-wallpaper-saucy
         </b>
       </p>
       
       <h4 style="font-weight:bold;font-size:1.5em;margin-top:1.5em;margin-bottom:1.0em;">Change the theme using Unity Tweak Tool:</h4>
       <p>
         Once you have installed the theme or extracted the content in ~/.themes directory, start Unity Tweak Tool. Go to Unity Dash and search for Unity Tweak tool:
         <br />
         <br />
         <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://itsfoss.itsfoss.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Unity-Tweak-Tool.jpeg" />
         <br />
         <br />
         
         You’ll find the Theme option in the Appearance section.
         <br />
         <br />
         <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://itsfoss.itsfoss.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Unity_tweak_tool_1.jpeg" />
         <br />
         <br />
         Once you have selected the Themes option, you will find all the themes present in the system here. Just click on the one you like. 
         It will be changed instantly. If you want, you can choose to change the icons only from the Icon tab. 
         I prefer to keep the default icons supplied with the theme.
         <br />
         <br />
         <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://itsfoss.itsfoss.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Chnage-Theme-Ubuntu.png" />
         <br />
         <br />
         And here is a screenshot of Numix theme in Ubuntu 13.10. The image is compressed a lot but you can still see the beauty:
         <br />
         <br />
         <img style="max-width:100%;" src="http://itsfoss.itsfoss.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Numix_theme_Ubuntu.jpeg" />
         <br />
         <br />
         That’s it. That is all you have to do to install Ubuntu desktop themes. 
         Now, if you are wondering where can I get Ubuntu themes, I would suggest you to look on Gnome Look. 
         Most of the GTK based themes will be supported in Unity. 
         Stay tuned for upcoming article of best themes for Ubuntu 13.10. Any questions, suggestions are most welcomed.
       </p>
    ]]>
  </c:content>
</c:component>