<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<c:component type="chSourceHighlighting" componentId="chSourceHighlighting_1" xmlns:c="http://com.snnmo.website">
  <c:abstract>
    <![CDATA[
<div style="font-size:1.1em;line-height:1.625;">
Many of the institutions we depend on as a modern society like hospitals, banks, stock exchanges and airports, need highly reliable and available computer systems to work. Unfortunately, single machines are not up to the task; they’re susceptible to crashes and downtime, and need regular maintenance. The solution, of course is to have multiple machines doing the same job, but how do we get them to do so? This is not a simple problem; the network connections between the machines are not reliable, the machines themselves may crash and we don’t want to involve people to fix things at 3 AM on a Sunday. Consensus is a fundamental part of building replicated systems and getting these machines to work together. The idea of getting them to work together is to have them all store the same data or commands in their logs. This increases the overall system reliability, because if one machine fails, another machine can take up its work.
</div>
]]>
  </c:abstract>


  <c:entry style="margin-top:1em;color:rgb(175, 0, 190);font-size:2.2em;">
    <c:title id="Reproduce-the-connection-reset-by-peer-error">TL;DR</c:title>
    <c:desc>
      <c:desc1> <![CDATA[]]></c:desc1>
    </c:desc>
    <c:sourceContent type="html" title="" id="sourceContent1" style="background-color:transparent;"
                     titleStyle="padding-left:0;color:black;font-size:1.8em;background-color:white;"
                     bodyStyle="padding:0;font-size:1em;line-height:1.825;font-family:monospace;">
      <![CDATA[
<div>
We are ready to stitch together our email confirmation flow, but how do we roll it out <b>without disrupting our service</b>?
</div>
<div style="margin-top:.625em;">
We approach the topic of zero downtime deployments: what it takes (<code>load balancers</code>), how it impacts the way we sequence our work (e.g. database migrations).
</div>
<div style="margin-top:.625em;">
By the end of the chapter, after a few red-green-refactor iterations, we'll finally get to deploy the new feature.
</div>
    ]]>
    </c:sourceContent>
    <c:comment>
      <c:comment1>
        <![CDATA[]]>
      </c:comment1>
    </c:comment>
  </c:entry>

</c:component>
